Guide to the William L. Mertz transportation collection, 1955-1990
George Mason University Libraries
- William L. Mertz transportation collection
  - Future Program Work Plan 4/2/87 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    Includes a short draft description of each of the 19 subordinate working papers.
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 1 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    Changing Demographics and Economic Use
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 2 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    Trends and Forecasts of Highway Passenger Travel
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 3 4/88 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    Trends and Forecast of Highway Freight Travel
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 4 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    Advancements in Highway materials and Construction Technology
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 5 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    Advancements in Automobile Technology
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 6 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    Advancements in Motor Truck Technology
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 8 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    Advancements in Telecommunications and Computer Technology Affecting Highway Travel
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 9 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    National Defence Highway Requirements
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 10 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    Urban and Suburban Highway Congestion
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 12 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    Highway Requirements for Freight Movement
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 12/87 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    Highway Performance and Investment Analysis
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 16 2/88 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    Federal Highway Investment Program Structure
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 17 2/88 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    Federal Mandates for Highway Operations and Safety
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 18 2/88 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    State, Local and Private Highway Roles
  - The Future National Highway Program, 1990 and Beyond: Working Paper 19 2/88 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    External Federal Policies and Motor Carrier Safety Laws and Regulations Affecting The Highway Program
  - Grid lock in Suburbia 6/3/88 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Halfway to 2020 5/12/88 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Highways and the Economy 1/83 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Highway Safety Priorities to the Year 2000 6/87 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - History of the United States Highway Program [bullet talking points] (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - How to Measure the Impact that the Office of Motor Carriers' Safety Programs have on Motor Carrier Safety 12/6/89 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - The Utility of Maintaining Detached Offices in the New York Division of Motor Carriers 11/21/89 (Box 25)
  - The Impact of declining mobility in Major Texas and Other US Cities 8/88 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Improving the Management of national Transportation Policy 4/23/88 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - Intercity and Interstate Travel and Network Connectivity (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Intercity Freight Cluster Group Outreach Plan (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - Intercity Connectivity / Rural Accessibility (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - ASSHTO Task Force on 2020 Consensus Transportation Program - Economic Development 1/89 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Interstate Highway Research Project - ANALYSIS 1990 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    195 pages; History
  - Interstate Highway Research Project - SOURCES 1990 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Interstate System Celebrates 30th Anniversary 1989 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - issues in Transportation and Growth Management 8/15/88 (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - Jammed in Jersey 4/23/88 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - In the Shadow of a Giant: H. S. Fairbank and the Development of Highway Planning (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - A Look at the Future - Conference on Long Range Trends and requirements for the Nation's Highway and Public Transit Systems 6/30/88 (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - The Answers: NoVA District Policy Makers Establish Objectives 3/25/88 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - Make Them Pay 2/18/89 (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - Making it Work 10/24/87 (Box 25, Folder 59)
    Representative Robert Roe and his stand on funding public works
  - Mission and Mix: A Study of the Changing Tasks and Staffing Requirements of the California Department of Transportation 1/87 (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - Motor Carrier Safety Workshop 3/26-27/86 (Box 25, Folder 61)
  - Motor Carrier Futures 8/26/88 (Box 25, Folder 62)
  - Office of Motor Carrier Automated Information Management Systems 6/89 (Box 25, Folder 63)
  - A Moveable Feat 2/89 (Box 25, Folder 64)
    humorous discussion of chauffer perk
  - Myths and Facts About Transportation and Growth 1989 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - A National Congestion Monitoring Plan (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - The National Transportation Demonstration Survey: Implications for National Policy 1989 (Box 25, Folder 67)
  - Commercial Vehicle Safety 5/23/89 (Box 25, Folder 68)
  - the Need for a New Vision of Our Urban Future 1989 (Box 25, Folder 69)
  - Origin and Growth of Motor Carrier Safety Responsibilities of the Federal Government (1935 -1986) 6/89 (Box 25, Folder 70)
  - Penn Jersey Transportation Study (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Perestroika for US Highways: A Bold New Policy for Managing Roads for a Free Society 11/90 (Box 25, Folder 72)
    deals with ownership and funding of transportation infrastructure
  - Pork: A Time-Honored Tradition Lives On 10/24/87 (Box 25, Folder 73)
  - A Possible Federal Surface Transportation Program for the coming Decades 1/28/88 (Box 25, Folder 74)
  - Post Interstate Transportation Program 1989 (Box 25, Folder 75)
  - Programs to Alleviate Traffic congestion 7/28/88 (Box 25, Folder 76)
  - Proposed Policy recommendations on the Direction of Future Federal Surface Transportation Program 10/98 (Box 25, Folder 77)
  - Proposed Post-Interstate Highway Program 6/88 (Box 25, Folder 78)
    Interstate Travel; Metropolitan Area Transportation; Small Urban and Rural Access; Highway and Traffic Safety; Highway Program Management
  - Rail Transit 3/88 (Box 25, Folder 79)
  - Records Management and Archival Practices In State Departments of Transportation Relevant to the History of the Interstate Highway System 1990 (Box 25, Folder 80)
  - Results of the Survey of the Chief Administrative Officers Regarding Alternatives for Transportation 2020 6/30/88 (Box 25, Folder 81)
  - Semitrailer Lengths Grand fathered and Current (2/16/89) State Law 2/16/89 (Box 25, Folder 82)
  - Statement of Carlton C. Robinson Before the Commission on the Future of Montgomery County 3/7/88 (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - Successful Cities Six Case Studies in Transportation Progress 1971 (Box 25, Folder 84)
  - Strategies to Alleviate Traffic Congestion 4/25-26/88 (Box 25, Folder 85)
  - The Status of the Nation's highways and Bridges: Conditions and Performance and Highway Bridge Replacement and Rehabilitation Program 1989 1/26/89 (Box 25, Folder 86)
  - Summary of issues/Points Made at the 2020 Forums in States in Region 9 (Box 25, Folder 87)
  - Summary of Results From Highway Performance Monitoring System Analysis (Box 25, Folder 88)
  - Supply and Use of the nation's Urban Highways 7/88 (Box 25, Folder 89)
  - Surface Transportation Futures: Searching for a New Consensus (Box 25, Folder 90)
  - Transportation Alternatives Group Issue Statement (Box 25, Folder 91)
  - The Task Force to Define the System of National Significance 12/19/88 (Box 25, Folder 92)
  - Thoughts on the Future of the Highway Program [draft of a speech] 1/27/88 (Box 25, Folder 93)
  - A Toolbox for Alleviating Traffic Congestion 1989 (Box 25, Folder 94)
  - TPB Assists in Developing a Sub-regional Transportation Plan for Northern Virginia 1988 (Box 25, Folder 95)
  - Transportation and Economic Development 1988 (Box 25, Folder 96)
  - Transportation Safety in 2020 5/88 (Box 25, Folder 97)
  - Transportation 2020 America's Future Depends on It 11/4/87 (Box 25, Folder 98)
  - Upon Shoulders of a Giant: Thomas MacDonald and the Federal-Aid Program 10/89 (Box 25, Folder 99)
  - Urban Freeway Gridlock Study 1988 (Box 25, Folder 100)
  - Urban Rail Transit Projects: Forecast Versus Actual Ridership and Costs 10/89 (Box 25, Folder 101)
  - The Urban Transportation Monitor 4/28/88 (Box 25, Folder 102)
    Politics Negatively Affect Transportation Profession; "Megabus" Claimed as a Low Cost alternative to Light Rail; Minimum Drinking Age Laws Have Saved Lives; FHWA Receives Comments on National Highway-Railroad Crossing Study
  - Urban Transportation System Performance Measures 8/19/87 (Box 25, Folder 102)
  - The Washington Metropolitan Areas Road System - Characteristics and Use 12/27/85 (Box 25, Folder 103)
  - Functional Classification Description for Principal arterial System 5/11/18 (Box 25, Folder 104)
  - Access America--A vision for the Next Federal-aid Highway Program 5/20/87 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - additional Urban Routes Approved for Interstate Highway System 9/29/55 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - the Best from American Canals 8/83 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - American Trucking Associations - Report to Members (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report 1968 - Tri-State Transportation Commission 1968 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - For Assessing Heavy Truck Safety 4/90 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - The Atlanta Success Story 1989 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - The Benefits of Improving Public Transit: A Myth or Fiction 9/15/92 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Calculation of Trees (Minimum Path Routes 9/60 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of Appreciation and Congratulatory Letters (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Commercial Vehicle Safety Alliance (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - 89 Condition and Performance (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Criticism of 2020 Consensus Transportation Program 6/28/88 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Changing Data Needs to meet our National Transportation Goals (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Community Forums on Total Transportation in the Phoenix Area 5/22/72 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Construction of the Alaska Highway 1975 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - A Message on the Importance of the Highway Infrastructure to U.S. Economic Growth and Productivity 7/16/91 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Criteria for Selection of Additional Interstate System Routes at Urban Areas 6/9/55 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Allegheny Portage Railroad 3/83 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Chronological index of Abstracts Related to IS Policy (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Employer Trip Reduction Draft Guidance 9/6/91 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - expressway Research Foundation of Japan 9/19 - 10/9/83 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Federal Funds Spent Properly 9/16 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    control of "pork barrel"
  - Federal Highway Administration NEWS Vol. 3, # 5 5/19/69 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    brief summary of W.L. Mertz career starting in 1949
  - Federal Highway Administration NEWS Vol. 3, # 11 11/20/69 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    Includes information regarding Mertz's involvement in 2 week urban transportation course
  - Federal Highway Administration NEWS 12/76 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    Information on the New River Gorge Bridge
  - Federal Highway Administration NEWS 5/80 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    New Look Road signs; Sulphur to Conserve Asphalt;Bicycle Paths;55 mile per hour speed limit;100 mile an hour super highway proposed
  - Federalism and Decentralization 11/6/74 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - A History of Oregon Autobile Insurance Company (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - The First Instrument Landing (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Geographic Aspects of Information Retrieval 9/26/64 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - High Speed Continuous Flow Person Conveyors 6/68 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Highway and Bridge Finance; System Conditions and Performance 8/12/91 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Highway Development Under the New Federal Legislation 1/30/46 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Highway Engineer Training Program, Your Road to Success 2/83 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Highway Needs (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Highway Program Criteria 1/6/88 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - The Highway Program (Box 26, Folder 38)
    draft of speech, brief discussion of cost and projection of future
  - AASHTO Task Force on 2020 [reaction to AASHTO draft report] 2/5/88 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - The 2020 Top 20 - A Preliminary Summary of Wisconsin 2020 Testimony to Date (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - [Houston,TX] Activity Centers and Worker Travel Characteristics [Study] (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Impact Assessment,Citizen Participation, and the Revolution in Transportation Planning (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Joint Highway-Transit Program (Impact of 1973 Highway Legislation) Spring 1973 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - July 1 Meeting Materials [ AASTO internal memo on Transportation 2020] 6/23/88 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - Chap 10: The Impact of National Urban Highway Policy on the Region (Box 26, Folder 45)
    Abstract of documents from 1944 to 1973
  - The Future National Highway Program 1991 and Beyond: Intercity and Interstate 4/88 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - Incremental Auto Insurance 3/6/93 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - 1919: The Interstate Expedition 8/73 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - [AASHTO] Interstate Highway [Historical] Research Project 9/8/90 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - D.C. Interstate System Route Adjustments 8/13/69 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - Involvement of Public Utilities in Transportation 5/20/70 (Box 26, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence Regarding a Trip to Japan 10/7/83 - 12/2/83 (Box 26, Folder 52)
  - Documents Relating to Mr. Mertz's Trip to Kuwait 1958 - 1973 (Box 26, Folder 53)
  - National Geographic request for editorial assistance 8/12/87 (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - List of MacDonald's Speeches (Box 26, Folder 55)
  - Making Transportation Choices Based on Real Costs 10/6/91 (Box 26, Folder 56)
  - Our Man in Germany [Lucius D Clay] 8/19/90 (Box 26, Folder 57)
  - Materials Transferred to Virginia Highway and Transportation Research Council 1/87 (Box 26, Folder 58)
  - 1840 - the National Pike or Cumberland Road (Box 26, Folder 59)
  - The National System of Interstate and Defense Highways: Improvement Status as of 6/30/85 6/30/85 (Box 26, Folder 60)
  - New York Governor Spoke Out (of Turn) 1/1/1829 (Box 26, Folder 61)
    reprint of an historical letter from Governor Martin Van Buren to President Andrew Jackson protesting the spread of a new form of transportation "railroads"
  - New York City Subway System Jubilee 9/79 (Box 26, Folder 62)
  - Minutes of the "No Name Group" 4/7/88 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Noerr Motor Freight, Inc. Et Al vs Eastern Railroad President's Conference Et Al 6/23/88 (Box 26, Folder 64)
  - Northern Virginia Travel Mode Trends Spring 1986 (Box 26, Folder 65)
  - Notes Taken From NCPC [National Capitol Planning Commission] Minutes 1952 - 1959 11/1/82 (Box 26, Folder 66)
  - Personal 1949 - 1987 (Box 26, Folder 67)
    various documents Mertz kept regarding his career: initial appointment document, political appointment notice, retirement party
  - Presentation of the Bartlett award to William Randolph Hearst, Jr. 1/1956 (Box 26, Folder 68)
  - Profiles: The Analytical Engine part I and II (Box 26, Folder 69)
    a detailed article on computation and "electronic computer capabilities"; includes the authors personal experiences with FORTRAN and programing skills
  - Correspondence from Mertz to AASHO Regarding Highway Planning Money 10/28/75 (Box 26, Folder 70)
    Corrects a misstatement regarding the flow of planning money within the states
  - Productivity and Consumer Benefits of Longer Combination Vehicles 6/90 (Box 26, Folder 71)
  - Proposed Reorganizations 1959-1963 (Box 26, Folder 72)
  - Memo from President Jimmy Carter to Brock Adams 3/21/77 (Box 26, Folder 73)
    States preference for inexpensive public transportation solutions
  - The Rise of the Interstates fall 1991 (Box 26, Folder 74)
  - Research and the Engineer 12/3/64 (Box 26, Folder 75)
  - A Reporter At Large: Painting the Elephant 6/25/84 (Box 26, Folder 76)
    a report of efforts to improve the NYC subways in early 1980's
  - Road Work -- A New Highway Policy 11/21/88 (Box 26, Folder 77)
  - Some Speculations Regarding Rapid Transit 11/1895 (Box 26, Folder 78)
  - A Ramble into the Past on the East Broad Top Railroad 1979 (Box 26, Folder 79)
  - The State of Interstates 8/86 (Box 26, Folder 80)
  - Special Purchase of Automatic Data Plotters 4/29/64 (Box 26, Folder 81)
  - Statement of William L. Mertz Before House Subcommittee on Government Activities and Transportation [van pools] 6/8/77 (Box 26, Folder 82)
  - A Study of Traffic Characteristics in Suburban Residential Areas 8/57 (Box 26, Folder 83)
  - The Surface Transportation Assistance Act of 1982: Shot Term Hopes and Long Term Implications 7/86 (Box 26, Folder 84)
  - Synthetic Geography: The Nature of Our Understanding of Cities 1/8/85 (Box 26, Folder 85)
  - [Transportation] System of National Significance 11/22/88 (Box 26, Folder 86)
  - TRB Session 187 - Data Requirements for National Planning 1/13/88 (Box 26, Folder 87)
  - Testimony of F. C. Turner on Federal-Aid Highway Program to House Subcommittee on Investigations and Oversight 6/15/71 (Box 26, Folder 88)
  - Tallying Traffic's Hidden Costs 3/6/93 (Box 26, Folder 89)
  - Technology and Fuel Efficiency spring 1990 (Box 26, Folder 90)
  - Tri-Statements 3/68 (Box 26, Folder 91)
    a description of the Tri - State "Technical Division" structure and functions.
  - A Touring We Will Go 6/28 (Box 26, Folder 92)
    describes road conditions supporting vacation touring
  - Traffic Generation by Suburban Residential Areas 1955 (Box 26, Folder 93)
  - Transportation Productivity 7/22/91 (Box 26, Folder 94)
  - the Unified Transportation Assistance Act of 1974 (Box 26, Folder 95)
  - Urban Transportation Planning - Unified Urban Work Program 3/17/72 (Box 26, Folder 96)
  - Urban Transportation Planning - Federal-Aid Highway Project Approvals in Urban Areas Over 50,000 Population 4/13/71 (Box 26, Folder 97)
  - Urban Transportation Planning Course 5/70 (Box 26, Folder 98)
  - Urban Transportation Requirements in Japan and Pilot Energy Study in Tokyo 12/78 (Box 26, Folder 99)
  - Urban Transportation Planning - Joint Funding Comprehensive Planning Programs Using H and PR Funding 11/10/70 (Box 26, Folder 100)
  - UTAP (Box 26, Folder 101)
    summary of "UTAP" LEGISLATION
  - The View From Here (Box 26, Folder 102)
    describes planning as seen by Mr. Mertz
  - [Jerre Hinkle Designs an Experiment] (Box 26, Folder 103)
    a poem presumably about a co-worker of Mr. Mertz
  - Letter from AASHTO to FHWA commenting on CBO study on Transportation 2020 12/12/98 (Box 26, Folder 104)
  - Past Policy Investigations 5/2/78 (Box 26, Folder 105)
  - What Tri-State is Doing 10/67 (Box 26, Folder 106)
  - What's Wrong with U.S. Transportation Infrastructure? 11/81 (Box 26, Folder 107)
  - Traffic Safety 5/21/63 (Box 26, Folder 108)
  - The Use of UNIVAC in processing and Analyzing Origin-Destination Data for the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Area 3/5/57 (Box 26, Folder 109)
  - Applying New Electronic Computers to Traffic and Highway Problems 7/57 (Box 26, Folder 110)
  - Thanks Chief (Box 26, Folder 111)
    a tribute to Thomas H. MacDonald upon retirement as U.S. Commissioner of Public Roads
  - Highway Fact Sheet [1978] (Box 26, Folder 112)
  - Consultation on the Conditions and Performance of Highways 1984 (Box 26, Folder 113)
    Based on terms for reimbursement, this appears to be a consultation provided by Mr. Mertz and Mr. Reulein to Nihon Doro Kodan of Japan
  - 30 Years on Ike's Autobahns (Box 26, Folder 114)
  - Your Review of Major Policy Principles/Options 7/15/88 (Box 26, Folder 115)
    Transportation 2020 correspondence forwarding Major categories of issue-related policies and options for each
  - Letter from Highway Users Federation to AASHTO 7/9/88 (Box 26, Folder 116)
  - Notes for a presentation to the Chinese delegation (Box 26, Folder 117)
  - Cooperative Research Programs 8/15/88 (Box 26, Folder 118)
  - The Bottom Line: A Summary of Surface Transportation Investment Requirements 1988-2020 6/88 and amp 9/88 (Box 26, Folder 119)
  - County Acts Now to Avert Gridlock (Box 26, Folder 120)
    Charlotte County
  - Notes for a speech regarding events in early 1971 [January 1971] (Box 26, Folder 121)
    views touch topics of revenue sharing, law passed 12/31/70, environmental impact statements
  - Why Do We Need to Stop Question 1 1991 (Box 26, Folder 122)
    a brochure opposing a referendum on transportation in Maine
  - AASHO letter announcing the burial of MacDonald 4/11/57 (Box 26, Folder 123)
    includes brief summary of MacDonald's career and contributions to Federal Highway program.
  - Kansas State College of Agriculture and Applied Science Commencement Program 5/29/49 (Box 26, Folder 124)
    Mertz listed as receiving a Bachelor degree in Civil Engineering
  - Kansas State Engineer 4/49 (Box 26, Folder 125)
    Col of Engineering magazine includes a short biography of Mertz
  - Public Works Historical Society Newsletter Spring 1985 and Spring 1987 (Box 26, Folder 126)
  - Draft Text for a Department of Transportation International Brochure 2/8/88 (Box 26, Folder 127)
  - Comments on FHWA on the status of highways and bridges 1989 3/6 and 3/7/89 (Box 26, Folder 128)
  - Eno Foundation for Transportation, Inc. (Box 26, Folder 129)
    brochure describes the foundation's interest in funding transportation research and information
  - Basic Interview Questions for AASHTO Interstate Highway Research Project (Box 26, Folder 130)
  - Measures of Urban Congestion 11/9/69 (Box 26, Folder 131)
  - Relationship of Productivity and Public Infrastructure Investment 9/14/88 (Box 26, Folder 132)
  - Right of Way 2/71 (Box 26, Folder 133)
    includes an article written by Mertz; "Involvement of Public Utilities in Transportation'
  - Tales of the Pennsylvania Turnpike 9/9/84 (Box 26, Folder 134)
  - Seminar: Building Consensus: Historical Perspectives from the Interstate Highway experience (Box 26, Folder 135)
  - Study of Infrastructure 1/17/89 (Box 26, Folder 136)
  - Virginia Legislation Regarding Disposition of Transportation Funds 1986 (Box 26, Folder 137)
  - Gridlock in Suburbia 6/3/88 (Box 26, Folder 138)
  - FHWA National Interstate - 1987 Heavy Trucks (Box 26, Folder 139)
    map
  - Motor Carrier Management Information System: Accident History Analysis 12/8/89 (Box 26, Folder 140)
  - Transportation 2020 state forums 1987 (Box 26, Folder 141)
  - Chemist Lambasts Clean Air Act (Box 26, Folder 142)
  - Traffic Congestion 1989 (Box 26, Folder 143)
  - Modal Split Revisited 1/69 (Box 26, Folder 144)
    multiple modes of transportation
  - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 145)
  - [Photographs of bridge, located in central PA? circa mid 1970's? (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - [Mertz's Sigma Tau fraternity brothers] 3/17/49 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - How Urban Transportation Planning Began 2/92 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - The Bragdon Committee spring 1990 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - memories of 499 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    499 Pennsylvania Ave. Washington D.C. was the headquarters of The Regional Highway Planning Committee
  - AASHTO Interstate Highway Research Project: Interview with Mr. Lee W. Mertz 3/5 and 3/12/88 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    historical
  - Origins of the Interstate (Box 27, Folder 7)
    incomplete
  - Appraisal Detail [Mertz personal investments] 1/28/87 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Meeting with Howard Hanna and Ed Carlton 9/28/67 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Administrator's Note opportunity for the '90's (or the Dismal Science Speaks to Transportation and Economic Vitality 10/12/90 (Box 27, Folder 10)